TIMOTHY OBER

San Diego, CA 92123 | Phone: 858-926-9421 | Email: timothy.ober@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothyobersdca/ GitHub: https://github.com/tober65

SUMMARY

Software engineer with experience in stand-alone applications and web development. 8 years of industry experience, and 7 years working on personal projects gives me an advantage in my knowledge of code, process, and problem solving. I have spent the past 7 years self employed making apps and games, which shoes my ability to work independently. I recently finished a full-time, 3 month software bootcamp (where my projects received an A+ average grade) to dust off old skills and pick up some new ones.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, C++, C#, Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS, MySQL

Technologies: Perforce, Git, Linux/Unix, .NET, SQL, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, RESTful APIs,

¡Query, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, Google Lighthouse, Webpack, Agile/Scrum, JSON/XML

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Self Employed

Feb 2014 – Present

Worked on personal projects.

- Developed a sledding simulator using the Unity engine. It involved custom terrain, physics simulation, and audio communication. Written in C#.
- Developed a first person survival game, also using the Unity engine. It involved use of textures, sound, and animation, limited AI, player vision tracking, and physics simulation for multiple objects interacting with each other. Written in C#.
- Developed several apps for Android written in Java. This included the use of Google Optical Character Recognition, Google Maps, and web database APIs.
- Finished a 3-month, full-time software bootcamp for full stack web development

Software Engineer Viasat

Jul 2006 – Feb 2014

Carlsbad, CA

Filled a variety of roles as a software engineer including GUI design and development, Linux management and development, back-end server development, quality testing, and internal tools.

- Individually ported Joint Communication Stimulator (JCS) from Sun Microsystem OS/hardware to Linux/PC hardware with no previous Linux experience. This saved several thousand dollars on each new desktop system, gave access to modern tools and IDEs, and significantly improved quality, cost, compatibility, and speed of support and new development for JCS.
- Acted as the lead designer and developer of desktop application software through the full product lifecycle to implement the Mode S signal type, increasing manageable signals of the JCS by approximately 300%.

- Responsible for the design and implementation of server-client-database interfaces of a secure modem management and deployment project in a team of 4. Additionally took on existing debugging and QA issues that had fallen behind.
- Served on a 6 person team as the software engineer assigned to the Blue Force Tracking quality and test team to provide Linux customization support and create software tools for necessary tests. Met daily updating benchmarks and goals including night and weekend support and software releases.

PROJECTS

Donner Pass | https://tober6584.itch.io/donnerpass

A sledding game written in the Unity engine

- Collaborated with a team of 4 people to build a game in a week
- Primarily focused on code/scripts
- Used C#, Unity Engine

Brew Favs | https://github.com/chrisgshred/brewFavs | https://brewfavs.herokuapp.com

An app to track favorite beers and breweries

- Collaborated with a team of 4 people to write efficient, reusable components and back-end libraries.
- Participated in the full software development life cycle, including estimation, design, development, debug/testing, and deployment.
- Primary back-end web developer for this project; integrate with third-party vendors, APIs, and datasets.
- Used Javascript, Sequelize, jQuery, Node, Express, and Google Maps

BOL\$A | https://github.com/tober65/bolsa | https://bolsa-tober65.herokuapp.com/signup A stock picking app

- Collaborated with a team of 4 people, focusing on backend API and database use with Express/Node routing.
- Was active in the planning, building, troubleshooting, and deployment of the project.
- Used Express, Node, Mongoose/MongoDB, React.is

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: UC San Diego Extension, San Diego, CA - 2020

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

B.S. in Computer Science: California Polytechnic, San Luis Obispo, San Luis Obispo, CA - 2006